Guide to the Robert Mearns Yerkes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject Files, 1893-1967; Series II; 24.5 linear feet (59 boxes)
  - Publishers
    - Yale Publishing Association, Inc., 1924-1930 (Box 84, Folder 1637)
    - Yale University Press, 1925-1951 (Box 84, Folder 1638)
  - Reprints and reproducing
    - Permission for reproducing, 1958, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 1639)
    - Pricing pamphlet cases, 1903-1904 (Box 84, Folder 1640)
    - Reprints, acknowledgements of, 1902-1942 (Box 84, Folder 1641-1642)
    - Reprints, requests for, 1915-1947 (Box 84, Folder 1643-1645)
    - Reproduction of illustrations, etc., 1924-1947 (Box 84, Folder 1646-1648)
  - Research
    - Apparatus, 1910-1917 (Box 85, Folder 1649)
    - Chicks, incubators, bantams, 1909-1912 (Box 85, Folder 1650)
    - Color filters for monochromatic light, 1909-1915 (Box 85, Folder 1651)
    - Crows: requests for funds, 1913 (Box 85, Folder 1652)
    - Dancing mouse
      - Correspondence with H.H. Donaldson and C.S. Rossy, 1913-1916 (Box 85, Folder 1653)
      - "Descriptions and Genealogy of Dancing Mice", 1904-1916 (Box 85, Folder 1654)
      - "Die Funktionellen und Hirnanatomischen Befunde Bei Der Japanischen Tanzmans" by Taco Kuiper, 1913 (Box 85, Folder 1655)
      - Reprints by others, 1901-1941 (Box 85, Folder 1656)
    - Discussion of research and teaching, 1914 (Box 85, Folder 1657)
    - Earthworms, 1912-1934, undated (Box 85, Folder 1658)
    - Fears: anecdotes told by students to D. LaRue, 1912-1913 (Box 85, Folder 1659)
    - Frogs: unpublished parts of thesis "Habits, Instincts, and Reactions of the Frog", 1900 (Box 85, Folder 1660)
    - Frogs: quotation from Science Service on frogs' learning, 1939 (Box 85, Folder 1661)
    - Gonionemus materials, 1901-1907 (Box 85, Folder 1662)
    - Gonionemus materials, 1901-1907 (Box 86, Folder 1663-1665)
    - Grants, 1913-1915 (Box 86, Folder 1666)
    - Harvard, Laboratory of Animal Psychology, 1900-1902 (Box 86, Folder 1667-1668)
    - History of Comparative Psychology, undated (Box 86, Folder 1669)
    - Imitation, 1906, 1909 (Box 86, Folder 1670)
    - Labyrinth, 1906-1912, undated (Box 86, Folder 1671-1672)
    - Multiple choice apparatus, 1916-1933 (Box 86, Folder 1673-1674)
    - Problems, 1899-1941 (Box 86, Folder 1675)
    - Ring-dove color vision, 1914 (Box 86, Folder 1676)
    - Smith, Arthur M.: multiple stimulus chronograph, 1905 (Box 87, Folder 1677)
    - Test materials
      - Adolescent Point Scale: original materials, undated (Box 87, Folder 1678)
      - Boston State Hospital forms, undated (Box 87, Folder 1679)
      - Boston State Hospital: tests given by Edith Tetlow, L.A. Rouse, and Ralph B. Bryan, 1913-1914 (Box 87, Folder 1680)
      - Directions for use of Multiple Choice Method, undated (Box 87, Folder 1681)
      - Edgarton, J. Alfred: typescript of study of Tom, blind and deaf boy, 1914-1915 (Box 87, Folder 1682)
      - Examinations at Boston State Hospital, undated (Box 87, Folder 1683)
      - Insight test, 1923-1927 (Box 87, Folder 1684-1685)
      - Manuscripts of reports on work of Binet and Goddard, undated (Box 87, Folder 1686)
      - Tests: general, 1923-1942 (Box 87, Folder 1687)
    - Vision: materials and correspondence for Yerkes and Watson, "Methods of Studying Vision in Animals", 1907-1914 (Box 87, Folder 1688-1691)
    - Vision: materials and correspondence for Yerkes and Watson, "Methods of Studying Vision in Animals", 1913-1914 (Box 88, Folder 1692)
  - The Scott Company
    - Founding through disbanding, 1919-1923 (Box 88, Folder 1693)
    - Reports and bulletins, 1920 (Box 88, Folder 1694)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1924-1926 (Box 88, Folder 1695-1696)
    - Anthropoid research, 1927-1947 (Box 88, Folder 1697)
    - Application for grant in aid: Sidney L. Pressey, 1952 (Box 88, Folder 1698)
    - Committee on the Federal Government and Research, 1945-1949 (Box 88, Folder 1699-1703)
      - Reports from committee members, 1946-1948 (Box 88, Folder 1704-1706)
    - Federal research, 1945 (Box 88, Folder 1707)
    - International News and Communication, 1924-1927 (Box 88, Folder 1708-1709)
    - Intersociety Committee for a National Science Foundation, 1946-1948 (Box 89, Folder 1710)
  - Society of Experimental Psychologists, 1926-1952 (Box 89, Folder 1711-1716)
  - Teaching
    - Chicago, University of: outline for summer school course "Mental Measurement" Psychology 38A, 1921 (Box 89, Folder 1717)
    - Harvard
      - Applied Psychology record book, 1903-1909 (Box 89, Folder 1718)
      - Exams, 1914-1916 (Box 89, Folder 1719)
      - Freshmen advisees, 1910-1916 (Box 89, Folder 1720)
      - Holt and Yerkes, An Experimental Study of Sensation, laboratory guide for students, 1903 (Box 89, Folder 1721)
      - Outline of a Study of the Self by Yerkes and LaRue containing autobiography of A.N. Levin, 1914 (Box 89, Folder 1722)
      - Outlines for courses and lectures, 1903-1911 (Box 89, Folder 1723-1725)
      - Outlines for courses and lectures, 1910-1914, undated (Box 90, Folder 1726-1732)
      - Registers, 1906-1914 (Box 90, Folder 1733)
      - Student grades, copies of exams, 1909-1917 (Box 90, Folder 1734)
      - Student lists, copies of exams, 1903-1911 (Box 90, Folder 1735)
      - Tests given in Philosophy 21A, 1909-1910 (Box 90, Folder 1736)
    - Records of Psychology at Harvard and Yale, 1899-1932 (Box 91, Folder 1737)
  - Titchener, E.B.: correspondence concerning his papers at Cornell, 1961-1963 (Box 91, Folder 1738)
  - Ursinus College, 1893-1955 (Box 91, Folder 1739-1740)
    - New science building, 1928-1933 (Box 91, Folder 1741-1742)
  - War: World War I
    - Report of the Division of Psychology, 1918 (Box 91, Folder 1743-1747)
    - Documents on history of Psychological Examining in Army, 1917-1920 (Box 91, Folder 1748-1750)
    - Psychological Examining in the U. S. Army
      - Weekly reports, 1917-1918 (Box 91, Folder 1751)
      - Weekly reports, 1918 (Box 92, Folder 1752-1758)
      - Memos, 1917-1919 (Box 92, Folder 1759-1760)
      - Correspondence, 1918-1920, 1938 (Box 92, Folder 1761-1762)
      - Correspondence: hardship cases, criticism, 1918-1919 (Box 92, Folder 1763)
      - Original set of psychological examination materials, 1917-1918 (Box 92, Folder 1764)
      - Examiner's Guides, 1917 (Box 92, Folder 1765)
      - Examiner's Guides, 1917-1918 (Box 93, Folder 1766-1767)
      - "Short form" of exam, 1918 (Box 93, Folder 1768)
      - Test forms, 1918 (Box 93, Folder 1769-1771)
      - Book: preparation of, 1919 (Box 93, Folder 1772)
      - Book: preparation of, 1920-1921 (Box 94, Folder 1773-1774)
      - Book: lists of psychologists, 1919-1921 (Box 94, Folder 1775-1776)
      - Book: requests for, 1919-1921 (Box 94, Folder 1777)
      - Book on military psychology, 1919 (Box 94, Folder 1778)
      - Maps, directories, activities of psychologists, 1917-1939 (Box 94, Folder 1779-1781)
      - Clippings, 1917-1918 (Box 94, Folder 1782)
      - National School Service, 1918-1919 (Box 94, Folder 1783)
      - Plan for Rating and Classification of Soldiers in the Students' Army Training Corps, 1918 (Box 94, Folder 1784)
    - Committee on Classification of Personnel, 1917-1919 (Box 94, Folder 1785-1786)
    - Morale, 1918 (Box 94, Folder 1787)
  - War: Between Wars, Officers' Reserve Corps, 1919-1929 (Box 94, Folder 1788)
  - War: World War II
    - Defense: miscellaneous, 1939-1941 (Box 94, Folder 1789)
    - Military: miscellaneous, 1940-1945 (Box 95, Folder 1790)
    - Miscellaneous requests, 1939-1942 (Box 95, Folder 1791)
    - Memorandum to Secretary of War, 1941 (Box 95, Folder 1792-1793)
      See also: box 95, folder 1796
    - Appointment as expert consultant, 1941-1942 (Box 95, Folder 1794-1795)
    - Dr. Walter V. Bingham, 1940-1946 (Box 95, Folder 1796)
    - Dr. Robert A. Brotemarke, 1940-1942 (Box 95, Folder 1797)
    - Dr. Vannevar Bush, 1941-1943 (Box 95, Folder 1798)
    - Alvin C. Eurich, 1942-1943 (Box 95, Folder 1799)
    - Frank B. Jewett, 1940-1941 (Box 95, Folder 1800)
    - Frederick Osborn, 1941-1943 (Box 95, Folder 1801)
    - John McAuley Palmer, 1940-1945 (Box 95, Folder 1802)
    - National Research Council, Committee on Classification of Military Personnel, 1944-1945 (Box 95, Folder 1803-1804)
    - Articles on military psychology, science, and defense, 1940-1944 (Box 95, Folder 1805-1806)
    - Articles on vocational counseling and demobilization, 1942-1944 (Box 95, Folder 1807)
    - Reports and articles on military psychology, 1941-1943 (Box 95, Folder 1808)
    - Reports and articles on military psychology, 1944-1947 (Box 96, Folder 1809-1810)
  - Works by Yerkes
    - Almost Human, 1925-1952 (Box 96, Folder 1811-1812)
    - Army Mental Tests by Yerkes and Yoakum, 1919-1947 (Box 96, Folder 1813)
    - Bibliographies on psychological subjects, 1911-1930 (Box 96, Folder 1814)
    - Bibliography of publications, 1899-1965 (Box 96, Folder 1815)
    - Chimpanzee Intelligence and Its Vocal Expressions by Yerkes and Learned, 1924-1935 (Box 96, Folder 1816-1818)
    - Chimpanzee Life: A Laboratory Handbook, 1934-1936 (Box 96, Folder 1819)
    - Chimpanzees: A Laboratory Colony
      - Correspondence, 1941-1947 (Box 96, Folder 1820)
      - Financial, 1942-1953 (Box 96, Folder 1821)
      - General, 1943-1950 (Box 96, Folder 1822)
      - Permissions to reproduce, 1942 (Box 96, Folder 1823)
      - Reviews, 1943-1945 (Box 96, Folder 1824)
      - Japanese translation by Matsumoto, 1953-1958 (Box 96, Folder 1825)
    - "Chimpanzees as Servants of Science," radio broadcast, 1945-1947 (Box 96, Folder 1826)
    - The Dancing Mouse, 1911-1934, undated (Box 96, Folder 1827)
    - Encyclopedia Americana articles, 1916 (Box 97, Folder 1828)
    - The Great Apes
      - Bibliographical material, 1923-1929, undated (Box 97, Folder 1829)
      - General, 1928-1956 (Box 97, Folder 1830-1832)
      - Illustrations, 1928-1930 (Box 97, Folder 1833)
      - Publicity and reviews, 1929-1933 (Box 97, Folder 1834)
      - Royalty statements, 1930-1955 (Box 97, Folder 1835)
    - "Genetic Aspects of Grooming", 1932-1933 (Box 97, Folder 1836)
      - Grooming correspondence and notes, 1932-1935 (Box 97, Folder 1837)
      - Acknowledgements of article on grooming, 1933 (Box 97, Folder 1838)
    - A History of Psychology in Autobiography, 1928-1934 (Box 97, Folder 1839)
    - Introduction to Psychology, 1911-1938 (Box 97, Folder 1840-1841)
    - "Pierre Janet," biographical sketch for Year Book of the American Philosophical Society, 1947-1948 (Box 97, Folder 1842)
    - "Mental Evolution in the Primates," chapter in Human Biology, 1927-1942 (Box 98, Folder 1843)
    - The Mind of a Gorilla, Part 1, 1926-1927 (Box 98, Folder 1844)
    - The Mind of a Gorilla, Part 2, 1927-1928 (Box 98, Folder 1845)
    - The Mind of a Gorilla, Part 3, 1928-1929 (Box 98, Folder 1846)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1918-1937 (Box 98, Folder 1847)
    - Modes of Behavioral Adaptation in Chimpanzees to Multiple-Choice problems, 1934, 1938 (Box 98, Folder 1848)
    - "Multiple Births in Anthropoid Apes", 1934, undated (Box 98, Folder 1849)
    - Outline of a Study of the Self, 1914-1929 (Box 98, Folder 1850)
    - Papers in journals, 1897-1904 (Box 98, Folder 1851)
    - A Point Scale for Measuring Mental Ability by Yerkes, Bridges, and Hardwick, 1914-1923 (Box 98, Folder 1852-1853)
      - Inquiries about materials, 1914-1927 (Box 98, Folder 1854-1856)
      - Work sheets, undated (Box 98, Folder 1857)
    - A Point Scale for Measuring Mental Ability revised edition, by Yerkes and Foster, 1922-1933 (Box 98, Folder 1858)
    - Psychological Examining in the U.S. Army, 1921-1947 (Box 98, Folder 1859)
    - "Psychology and Defense", 1941 (Box 98, Folder 1860)
    - "Psychology in its Relation to Biology", 1909-1910 (Box 98, Folder 1861)
    - Regulations of Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology, 1932-1938 (Box 99, Folder 1862)
    - Reprints, 1927, 1941 (Box 99, Folder 1863)
    - Reviews by Yerkes, 1925-1943 (Box 99, Folder 1864)
    - "The Scope of Science", 1947 (Box 99, Folder 1865)
    - "Sensations of Lower Animals and Plants", 1909-1916 (Box 99, Folder 1866)
    - "The Significance of Chimpanzee culture for Biological Research," Harvey Lecture, 1935-1936 (Box 99, Folder 1867)
    - "Social Behavior of Infra-Human Primates," chapter in Handbook of Social Psychology Murchison, 1933-1937 (Box 99, Folder 1868)
    - "Testament"
      - Correspondence with critics and publishers, 1947-1956 (Box 99, Folder 1869-1870)
      - Correspondence on ethics and religion, 1945-1947 (Box 99, Folder 1871)
      - Titles, preface, contents, chronology, 1946-1950 (Box 99, Folder 1872)
      - notes, undated (Box 99, Folder 1873)
      - Outline of parts, undated (Box 99, Folder 1874)
      - Abstracts, references, notes, undated (Box 99, Folder 1875-1876)
      - Religion and science, ethics, morals, undated (Box 99, Folder 1877)
      - Personal materials, undated (Box 99, Folder 1878)
      - Information from National Research Council, 1947 (Box 100, Folder 1879)
    - "Testing the Human Mind", 1923 (Box 100, Folder 1880)
    - "Yale Laboratories of Comparative Psychobiology", 1931-1932 (Box 100, Folder 1881)
    - "Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology", 1942-1943 (Box 100, Folder 1882)
    - Lectures, 1901-1952 (Box 100, Folder 1883-1891)
      - Westbrook lectures at Wagner Free Institute of Science, 1932-1933 (Box 100, Folder 1892)
      - "The Psychobiology of the Great Apes", 1937-1938 (Box 100, Folder 1893)
    - Manuscripts
      - Published manuscripts, 1923-1946 (Box 100, Folder 1894)
      - Requests for, 1904-1946 (Box 101, Folder 1895-1898)
      - Papers, 1900 (Box 101, Folder 1899)
      - Papers, unpublished, 1900-1916 (Box 101, Folder 1900)
      - Genetic psychology, proposed book on, Circa 1905 (Box 101, Folder 1901)
      - Harper & Brothers: correspondence concerning articles and Almost Human, 1910-1925 (Box 101, Folder 1902)
      - Atlantic and Saturday Evening Post articles, 1922 (Box 101, Folder 1903)
      - "Adventures in Psychology," unpublished personal account of psychological examining in the U.S. Army, 1922 (Box 101, Folder 1904)
      - Planned popular book on "Animals I Have Questioned", 1934 (Box 101, Folder 1905)
      - The Yale Review, 1937 (Box 101, Folder 1906)
      - "note on the Sexual Cycle and Behavior of an Orang-Outan" by Yerkes and John F. Fulton, 1939 (Box 101, Folder 1907-1908)
      - "Blue Print for American Education", 1943 (Box 101, Folder 1909)
        - Replies and comments, 1943-1946 (Box 101, Folder 1910-1913)
        - Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 101, Folder 1914)
      - Plan for postwar employment, 1944 (Box 102, Folder 1915)
      - "Reflections Concerning Psychology in a Liberal Arts Curriculum", 1945, 1949 (Box 102, Folder 1916)
      - Articles on instinct; unpublished, Circa 1901 (Box 102, Folder 1917-1918)
      - Miscellaneous articles, undated (Box 102, Folder 1919-1921)
      - Prostate operation, impublished, 1949-1950 (Box 102, Folder 1922)
  - Yale Laboratories of Primate Biology
    See: box 100, folder 1882
  - Yale University
    - Institute of Psychology
      - General, 1924-1930 (Box 102, Folder 1923-1924)
      - Annual reports, 1924-1929 (Box 102, Folder 1925-1926)
      - Budgets and minutes, 1924-1929 (Box 102, Folder 1927)
      - Applicants: general, 1923-1924 (Box 102, Folder 1928)
      - Applicants: research assistants and fellows, 1925-1929 (Box 102, Folder 1929-1931)
      - Manson barn, 1925-1930 (Box 103, Folder 1932-1934)
      - Psychological seminar, 1925-1930 (Box 103, Folder 1935)
      - Psychology 119: seminar in comparative and genetic psychology, 1925-1929 (Box 103, Folder 1936)
      - Copies of examinations, 1927-1928 (Box 103, Folder 1937)
    - Institute of Human Relations
      - Plans for "The Human Welfare Group", 1929 (Box 103, Folder 1938)
      - General, 1928-1931 (Box 103, Folder 1939-1940)
      - Construction plans for Laboratories of Comparative Psychobiology
        - Sterling Hall of Medicine extension, 1926-1930 (Box 103, Folder 1941-1944)
        - Specifications for lab furniture, 1930-1931 (Box 103, Folder 1945-1946)
        - Specifications for animal cages, 1931 (Box 103, Folder 1947-1948)
        - Correspondence with F.B. Johnson re: furniture, 1930-1931 (Box 103, Folder 1949)
        - Blueprints, undated (Box 103, Folder 1950-1952)
        - Blueprints, undated (Box 104, Folder 1953-1954)
      - Plans and budget for Laboratories of Comparative Psychobiology, 1928-1934 (Box 104, Folder 1955-1956)
      - Relations with Yale Laboratories of Primate Biology, 1929-1944 (Box 104, Folder 1957-1958)
      - Applicants: research, 1929-1931 (Box 104, Folder 1959)
      - Proposed Bureau of Human Standards, 1929 (Box 104, Folder 1960)
      - Department of Psychology, 1930-1931 (Box 104, Folder 1961)
      - Reports to department, 1930-1931 (Box 104, Folder 1962)
      - Revision of syllabus for pro-seminar, 1933 (Box 104, Folder 1963)
      - Seminar in Comparative Psychology, notebook for, 1931-1941 (Box 104, Folder 1964-1965)
      - Outlines for pro-seminar meetings, 1932-1941 (Box 104, Folder 1966)
    - Psychology Department
      - Pictures of members of department, 1940 (Box 104, Folder 1967)
      - Yale Psychology Group, 1929-1937 (Box 104, Folder 1968)
      - Committee on Psychologists in Government Service, 1941-1942 (Box 104, Folder 1969)
      - Committee on Clinical Psychology, 1944-1947 (Box 105, Folder 1970)
      - Committee on a Comprehensive Program for Psychology, 1945-1946 (Box 105, Folder 1971)
    - Yale University Library, 1927-1948 (Box 105, Folder 1972)
    - President Charles Seymour, 1937-1947 (Box 105, Folder 1973)
    - Secretary Carl Lohmann, 1927-1945 (Box 105, Folder 1974)
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1947 (Box 105, Folder 1975)
    - School of Medicine
      - Department of Psychology, 1938-1954 (Box 105, Folder 1976-1978)
      - Office relocation and inventory, 1943-1950 (Box 105, Folder 1979)
      - Information on postal rates, 1932-1952 (Box 105, Folder 1980)
      - Committees, 1936-1941 (Box 105, Folder 1981)
      - Dean's office, 1939-1945 (Box 105, Folder 1982-1984)
      - Annual reports to Dean, 1932-1944 (Box 105, Folder 1985-1986)
      - Resolution on RMY's retirement, 1944 (Box 105, Folder 1987)
      - Department of Anatomy, 1932-1943 (Box 105, Folder 1988-1990)
      - Department of Neuro-Anatomy, 1939-1942 (Box 105, Folder 1991)
      - Department of Physiological Sciences, 1939-1942 (Box 105, Folder 1992)
      - Executive Secretary: Miss Lottie Bishop, 1931-1947 (Box 105, Folder 1993-1994)
  - Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology
    - Advisory Board
      - James R. Angell, 1929-1939 (Box 106, Folder 1995-1996)
      - Stanhope Bayne-Jones, 1936-1937 (Box 106, Folder 1997)
      - Edwin G. Conklin, 1929-1930 (Box 106, Folder 1998)
      - Milton J. Greenman, 1929-1937 (Box 106, Folder 1999-2001)
      - Frank R. Lillie, 1935-1939 (Box 106, Folder 2002)
      - John C. Merriam, 1929-1937 (Box 106, Folder 2003-2004)
      - Theobald Smith, 1929-1934 (Box 106, Folder 2005)
      - H. Gideon Wells, 1929-1939 (Box 106, Folder 2006)
      - Clark Wissler, 1929-1937 (Box 106, Folder 2007)
      - Report of Committee on Appraisal and Recommendation, 1935 (Box 106, Folder 2008)
    - Administrative Committee, Minutes of Meetings, 1939-1942 (Box 106, Folder 2009-2010)
    - Animal Colony and records, 1925-1953 (Box 106, Folder 2011-2013)
    - Annual reports
      - 1-3, 1930-1932 (Box 107, Folder 2014)
      - 4-6, 1932-1935 (Box 107, Folder 2015)
      - 7-9, 1935-1938 (Box 107, Folder 2016)
      - 8, 1936-1937 (Box 107, Folder 2017)
      - 10-12, 1938-1941 (Box 108, Folder 2018)
      - 13, 1941-1942 (Box 108, Folder 2019)
      - 14, 1942-1943 (Box 108, Folder 2020)
      - 15, 1943-1944 (Box 108, Folder 2021)
      - 12, 16-19, 1940-1948 (Box 108, Folder 2022)
      - 20-23, 1948-1952 (Box 108, Folder 2023)
      - 24, 1952-1953 (Box 108, Folder 2024)
      - 24, 1953-1955 (Box 109, Folder 2025)
      - 25-26, 1953-1955 (Box 109, Folder 2026)
      - 27-29, 1955-1958 (Box 109, Folder 2027)
      - 30-32, 1958-1961 (Box 109, Folder 2028)
    - Business
      - Bills, 1942-1943 (Box 109, Folder 2029)
      - Bills, primate biology, 1943-1944 (Box 109, Folder 2030)
      - Budgets, 1932-1942 (Box 109, Folder 2031)
      - Insurance of chimpanzees in transit, 1930 (Box 109, Folder 2032)
      - Insurance of people and property, 1930-1942 (Box 109, Folder 2033)
      - Inventory, general, 1931-1942 (Box 109, Folder 2034-2035)
      - Property taxation, 1932-1940 (Box 109, Folder 2036-2037)
    - Director
      - Karl S. Lashley: program, 1940-1941 (Box 109, Folder 2038-2039)
      - Appointments to Board of Scientific Directors, 1942 (Box 110, Folder 2040)
      - Minutes of Board Meetings, 1942-1955 (Box 110, Folder 2041-2044)
      - Lashley, Karl S., 1942-1954 (Box 110, Folder 2045-2058)
      - Nissen, Henry W., 1955 (Box 110, Folder 2059-2060)
      - Nissen, Henry W., 1955-1958 (Box 111, Folder 2061-2062)
      - Period of Nissen and Lashley deaths, 1955-1959 (Box 111, Folder 2063)
    - Equipment, 1930-1939 (Box 111, Folder 2064-2068)
    - Financing
      - Memoranda on refinancing, 1939-1945 (Box 111, Folder 2069)
      - Abreu Fund, 1936, 1955 (Box 111, Folder 2070)
      - Rockefeller Foundation grants, 1928-1944 (Box 111, Folder 2071)
      - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1942 (Box 111, Folder 2072)
      - Contribution to funds from RMY, 1944 (Box 111, Folder 2073)
    - History
      - News release, 1942 (Box 111, Folder 2074)
      - Article by George Gray, 1954 (Box 111, Folder 2075)
    - Reports of Investigators, 1930-1936 (Box 111, Folder 2076-2078)
    - Secretarial Correspondence
      - Helen S. Morford, 1932 (Box 111, Folder 2079-2081)
      - Weller-Morford, 1933-1936 (Box 111, Folder 2082-2087)
      - Mayell-Morford, 1936-1937 (Box 111, Folder 2088-2089)
      - Mayell-Morford, 1939 (Box 112, Folder 2090)
      - Morford-Willey, 1939 (Box 112, Folder 2091-2092)
      - Laura Mayell Willey, 1941 (Box 112, Folder 2093)
      - Morford, Tomilin, Hewey, 1933-1945 (Box 112, Folder 2094-2097)
    - G.H.W. Schmidt re Orange Park plant, 1963 (Box 112, Folder 2098)
    - Staff
      - Applicants, 1931-1945 (Box 112, Folder 2099-2104)
      - Recommendation of Paul Guillaume, 1940-1941 (Box 112, Folder 2105)
      - Miscellaneous personnel, 1941-1943 (Box 112, Folder 2106)
      - Biographical data psychologists, undated (Box 112, Folder 2107)
      - List of Ph.D's, 1945 (Box 112, Folder 2108)
    - Students, Cooperative work with Dr. Fulton in physiology of chimpanzee, 1931-1940 (Box 112, Folder 2109)
  - Yerkes Regional Primate Research Center, 1962-1967 (Box 112, Folder 2110)
  - Zoos
    - Berlin Zoological Garden, 1928-1946 (Box 112, Folder 2111)
    - Bristol Zoological Gardens, 1935-1937 (Box 112, Folder 2112)
    - Chicago Zoological Park, 1941 (Box 112, Folder 2113)
    - Duesseldorf Zoological Garden, 1932-1933 (Box 112, Folder 2114)
    - Hannover Zoologischer Garten, 1935-1936 (Box 112, Folder 2115)
    - W.R. Hearst Zoo, 1935 (Box 112, Folder 2116)
    - London Zoological Garden, 1913-1934 (Box 113, Folder 2117)
    - McKee Jungle Gardens, 1939-1940 (Box 113, Folder 2118)
    - National Zoological Park, 1930-1931 (Box 113, Folder 2119)
    - New York Zoological Park, 1913-1956 (Box 113, Folder 2120-2127)
    - Philadelphia Zoological Garden, 1923-1946 (Box 113, Folder 2128-2130)
    - St. Louis Zoological Park, 1930-1940 (Box 113, Folder 2131)
    - San Diego Zoo, 1931-1947 (Box 113, Folder 2132-2135)
    - Toledo Zoological Society, 1932 (Box 113, Folder 2136)
    - Miscellaneous parks, 1923-1947 (Box 113, Folder 2137-2138)
- Experiments, 1900-1953; Series III; 2.75 linear feet (7 boxes)